RG 069:154, Bouton Family Letters and Sermons
Connecticut State Library
New Bern (N.C.); Annapolis (Md.); Concord (N.H.); Hartford (Conn.); New York (N.Y.); Carson City (Nev.); Norwalk (Conn.); Roanoke Island (N.C.); Bogue Banks (N.C.); Beaufort (N.C.)
Persons:
Bouton, Nathaniel, 1799-1878; Bouton, John B. (John Benedict), 1821-1895; Bouton, Harriet A., 1821-1903; Bouton, Archibald, 1850-1922; Bouton, Sarah M.; Bouton, Emily C.; Bouton, John Bell, 1830-1902
Document Types:
Correspondence; Diaries; Envelopes; Inventories; Photographs; Publications; Sermons
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
The Bouton family letters and sermons were donated by Brooke Ann Sammons Nielsen and Laurel Emily Bouton Sammons to the State Library in 2010.
Container List
- Series 1. Correspondence, 1825-1865
  - Correspondence - John B. Bouton, 1861-1864 (Box 1, Folder 1-13)
  - Correspondence - Nathaniel Bouton, 1856-1861 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Nathaniel Bouton to Harriet Bouton, 1865 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Sarah M. Bouton, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter to Daniel Weed at New Canaan, Connecticut from W. Weed, 1825 May 5 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Letter to Deacon John Bouton at Norwalk, Connecticut from George W. Betts, New York, 1827 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Betsy Bouton at Norwalk, Connecticut to Reverend Nathaniel Bouton at Concord, New Hampshire, 1835 May 16 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - John B. Bouton at Williamsburgh to Harriet A. Weed, 1848 February 4 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - John B. Bouton at Williamsburgh, New York to Harriet A. Weed, 1848 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Harriet Bouton to John B. Bouton at Annapolis, Maryland, 1862 January 12 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Harriet Bouton to John B. Bouton, 1862 January 26 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Harriet A. Bouton to John B. Bouton, 1862 February 9 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Harriet Bouton to John B. Bouton, 1862 February 22 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Harriet Bouton to John B. Bouton, 1862 March 23 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Harriet A. Bouton to John B. Bouton at Carolina City, North Carolina, 1862 April 21 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Series 2. Sermons, 1820-1827
  - Partial sermon by Reverend Nathaniel Bouton, 1820 March 6 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Covenant" sermon by Reverend Nathaniel Bouton, 1825 March 19 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Sermon by Reverend Nathaniel Bouton, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Article 4th" sermon by Reverend Nathaniel Bouton, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Article 5th" sermon by Reverend Nathaniel Bouton, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Sermon by Reverend Nathaniel Bouton, 1827 January 31 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series 3. Diary, 1861-1862
  - Excerpt of diary of John B. Bouton, 1861 November 3-1862 January 17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Series 4. Archibald Bouton, 1894
  - Mrs. A. Bouton inventory of silverware, 1894 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series 5. Publications, 2009
  - Bouton Family Letters and Sermons, 1820-1865, 2009 July 14; 1 volume bound in a black spiral plastic coil (Box 2)
- Series 6. Miscellaneous, circa 1861-1864
  - Envelopes, circa 1861-1864, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series 7. Photographs, 1861-1908
  - John B. Bouton, 1861. Company H, 8th Regiment Connecticut Volunteers. Born May 21, 1821; Died March 25, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    See also Bouton Family Letters and Sermons, 1820-1865 pages: iii, 1, 2.
  - Howard's last picture…almost 11 month's before his death. Baby in picture 7 months old, 1908 July (Box 3, Folder 2)
    See also Bouton Family Letters and Sermons, 1820-1865 pages: ix, 331, 333.
  - Archibald Bouton and John Bouton, circa 1896 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    See also Bouton Family Letters and Sermons, 1820-1865 pages: ix, 311.